(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-06T22:34:04.020901",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ホロライブに入る！！
[Note: Join hololive!!]
オーディション会場
[Sign: Audition Venue]
群青
[Song: Gunjou]
嗚呼、いつものように
Ah, as usual,
過ぎる日々に あくびが出る
I yawn at the passing days.
さんざめく夜、越え、今日も
Moving past a bustling night, today again
渋谷の街に朝が降る
morning descends upon the streets of Shibuya.
どこか虚しいような
Feeling somewhat empty,
そんな気持ち
such a feeling
つまらないな
is so boring.
でもそれでいい
But that's fine,
そんなもんさ
that's just how it is.
これでいい
This is fine.
知らず知らず隠してた
Without realizing it, I hid it away;
本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら
let your true voice ring out, come on.
見ないフリしていても
Even if you pretend not to see it,
確かにそこにある
it is definitely right there.
あぁ 感じたままに描く
Ah, painting just as I feel,
自分で選んだその色で
with the colors I chose myself.
眠い空気纏う朝に
In the morning draped in drowsy air,
訪れた青い世界
a blue world arrived before me.
好きなものを好きだと言う
Saying I love the things I love—
怖くて仕方ないけど
I was terribly scared, but
本当の自分
my true self,
出会えた気がしたんだ
I felt like I had finally met her.
嗚呼、手を伸ばせば伸ばすほどに
Ah, the further I stretch out my hands,
遠くへゆく
the farther away it goes.
思うようにいかない、今日も
Things don't go as planned; today, too,
また慌ただしくもがいてる
I'm hectically struggling once again.
悔しい気持ちも
Even feelings of frustration
ただ情けなくて
and feeling pathetic
涙が出る
make tears fall.
踏み込むほど
The further I step in,
苦しくなる
the more painful it gets,
痛くもなる
and it hurts, too.
あぁ 感じたままに進む
Ah, moving forward just as I feel,
自分で選んだこの道を
along this path I chose myself.
重いまぶた擦る夜に
On a night rubbing my heavy eyelids,
しがみついた青い誓い
I clung to a blue vow.
好きなことを続けること
Continuing to do what you love—
それは「楽しい」だけじゃない
that isn't just about "having fun."
本当にできる？
Can I really do it?
不安になるけど
I get anxious, but
あぁ 何枚でも
Ah, no matter how many canvases,
ほら何枚でも
look, no matter how many sheets,
自信がないから描いてきたんだよ
it's because I lacked confidence that I kept drawing!
あぁ 何回でも ほら
Ah, no matter how many times, look—
ああ 何回でも積み上げてきたことが武器になる
Ah, everything I've built up time and again will become my weapon.
周りを見たって 誰と比べたって
Even if I look around, even if I compare myself to others,
僕にしかできないことはなんだ
what is something that only I can do?
今だって 自信なんかない それでも
Even now, I have no confidence at all, but still...
感じたことない気持ち 知らずにいた想い
Emotions I've never felt before, feelings I never knew I had...
あの日 踏み出して
Taking that step forward on that day,
初めて感じたこの痛みも全部
even all this pain I felt for the first time...
好きなものと向き合うことで
By facing what I love head-on,
触れた まだ小さな光
I touched a faint, tiny light.
大丈夫 行こう あとは楽しむだけだ
It's alright, let's go. All that's left is to enjoy it!
ああ 全てを賭けて描く
Ah, I'll risk everything and paint
自分にしか出せない色で
in colors that only I can create.
朝も夜も走り続け
Running relentlessly day and night,
見つけ出した青い光
I found that blue light.
好きなものと向き合うこと
Facing what I love head-on
今だって怖いことだけど
is still terrifying even now, but
もう今は あの日 透明な僕じゃない
I am no longer the transparent me of that day.
ああ ありのままの
Ah, staying true to who I am,
かけがえのない僕だ
I am irreplaceable.
知らず知らず隠してた
Without realizing it, I hid it away,
本当の声を響かせてよ ほら
so let your true voice ring out, look!
見ないフリしていても
Even if you pretend not to see it,
確かにそこに 今もそこにあるよ
it's definitely right there, still there even now.
知らず知らず隠してた
Without realizing it, I hid it away,
本当の声を響かせてよ さあ
so let your true voice ring out, come on!
見ないフリしていても
Even if you pretend not to see it,
確かにそこに 君のなかに
it's definitely right there, inside of you.
Ah ah ah ah ah ah Hey
Ah ah ah ah ah ah
奪って奪って
Snatch it away, snatch it away,
脳みその中から「やめろ馬鹿」と喚くモラリティ
morality screams "stop, you idiot!" from inside my brain.
Darling Baby Darling
半端無く狂うと煌めき浮き足立つフィロソフィー
when it goes insanely wild, philosophy sparkles and gets restless.
死ぬほど可愛い？ 上目遣い
Deadly cute? Upturned eyes,
何かしらに触れるくらい ばら撒く乱視
scattering astigmatism enough to touch just about anything.
気付けば当時 この世に生まれた君が悪い
Before I knew it, you're the one to blame for being born into this world.
やたらとしんどい 恋患い
Exceedingly exhausting lovesickness,
バラバラな頭とこの身体
this shattered head and broken body.
頸動脈からアイラブユーを吐き出して アイ...
Spitting out "I love you" from my carotid artery, I...
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What do I do with these feelings?
肋骨の奥のザラメが溶けてケロイドになりそう
The brown sugar deep in my ribs is melting, about to become a keloid.
怒号 罵詈雑言 愚劣にそう
Roars of rage, abusive language, foolishly so,
今この世で君だけ大正解
right now in this world, you alone are the absolute correct answer.
Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling
ひっくり返っても勝ち目はない 君だけルールは適用外
Even turning things upside down, there's no chance of winning; you alone are exempt from the rules.
寄る辺も白黒しかない 風邪引く夜
Even my refuge is strictly black and white on this chilly night.
君が笑顔で放ったアバダケダブラで タブラ・ラサ
With the Avada Kedavra fired from your smile, tabula rasa,
泥水飲み干すにも申し訳ねえな
it feels almost rude to drink up muddy water.
容赦して 貫いて 「ここ弱点」
Have mercy, pierce through, "here's the weak spot."
死ぬほど可愛い？ 上目遣い
Deadly cute? Upturned eyes,
何かしらに触れるくらい ばら撒く乱視
scattering astigmatism enough to touch just about anything.
気付けば当時 この世に生まれた君が悪い
Before I knew it, you're the one to blame for being born into this world.
パチモンでもいい なんでもいい 今君となぞってる全て欲しい
Even a knockoff is fine, anything is fine, I want everything I'm tracing with you right now.
頸動脈からアイラブユーを吐き出して アイリスアウト
Spitting out "I love you" from my carotid artery, iris out!
Ah ah ah ah アイリスアウト
Ah ah ah ah, iris out!
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What do I do with these feelings?
肋骨の奥のザラメが溶けてケロイドになりそう
The brown sugar deep in my ribs is melting, about to become a keloid.
怒号 罵詈雑言 愚劣にそう
Roars of rage, abusive language, foolishly so,
今この世で君だけ大正解
right now in this world, you alone are the absolute correct answer.
Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling
La ah ah...
しゅぴしゅわ〜！ スーの充電足りてる〜？
Shupishuwa~! Are you fully charged with Suu energy?
ホロライブDEV_IS、FLOW GLOWの、いろいろ担当、水宮すうでーす！
From hololive DEV_IS's FLOW GLOW, in charge of variety, I'm Suzu Minase!
ということで、STEP INTO DREAMS始まりましたー！ イエーイ！
And with that, "STEP INTO DREAMS" has begun! Yay!
今回はですね、オープニングにもあった通り、
So for today, just like in the opening,
夢だった、ホロライブに入って夢だった、初めてのソロ生...
it's been my dream ever since joining hololive, my very first solo live...
生誕ライブー！それー、いぇーーい！
My Birthday Live! Here we go, yay!
ちょっと めちゃめちゃに緊張しているんですけれども、
I'm super nervous right now, but...
どうだった？Gunjo with Iris Out
How was "Gunjo with Iris Out"?
コメント欄どうだった？かっこよかった？
How was it in the comments? Was it cool?
かっこよかったってきっと、まあこの後流れるんだろうな。
I'm sure comments saying "it was cool" will start flowing soon.
かっこよかっただろう！
I bet it was cool, right!
いっぱい褒めてください！
Please shower me with compliments!
今回はですね、タイトルにもある通り、
This time, just as the title says,
もうステップが、もうはちゃめちゃに、もうステップが、ステップがもうはちゃめちゃに多かったりですね、
there were crazy amounts of steps in the dance routines,
あとは、やったことのないジャンルのダンスにも挑戦しちゃったりしていますので、
and I'm also challenging dance genres I've never tried before,
お楽しみにー！
so please look forward to it!
ハッシュタグは、こちらにある #水宮すう生誕祭2026 です！
The hashtag is #MizumiyaSuBirthdayFestival2026 right up here!
スクショとか、感想とかたーくさんポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you post tons of screenshots and your thoughts!
目指せ、トレンド！
Let's aim to trend!
みんな、いっぱいポストしてねー！
Everyone, post lots and lots!
この後はですね、ゲストパートにも行きたいと思っているの...
Next up, I was planning to move on to the guest part...
ですが、
...however,
なんと！お祝いの映像が届いてるみたいなので、見てみましょうー！
it seems a congratulatory video has arrived, so let's watch it!
こっちかな？
Over this way?
よし！
Alright!
なんだなんだ？あっ！
What is it, what is it? Ah!
君を笑顔へご案内！蘭楓の観光大使で、にじさんじ所属、綾柿のしっぽ、紫刈湖だよー！
Guiding you to smiles! Ranfu's tourism ambassador from NIJISANJI, Aya-kaki no Shippo, Shigariko here!
リコー！
Riko-!
水宮ー！お誕生日おめでとーー！
Mizumiya! Happy birthday!
ありがとうーー！
Thank you!
今頃は水宮は最高なライブをしていることでしょうー！
Right about now, Mizumiya must be putting on the best live show ever!
そうかなー？
You think so~?
本当におめでとー！
Huge congratulations!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
本当はね、現地で直接お祝いがしたかったんですけど、
I really wanted to celebrate with you directly on stage, but...
ちょっとどうしてもスケジュールが合わないということで、お祝いのメッセージ動画をね、今回送らせていただいております！
our schedules just didn't align, so I'm sending this video message to celebrate!
水宮とはね、「どろめろ」としてもたくさんコラボして、
With Mizumiya, we've done so many collabs as "Doromero",
プライベートとかでもテーマパーク行ったりとか、映画行ったりとか、
and in private we've gone to theme parks and movies together,
行ったー！行ったー！
We did! We did!
もう月イチでお泊まりするくらいの、
and we even have sleepovers like once a month...
うん！
Yeah!
仲良くね、させてもらってて、もう本当にいつもありがとー！
We're so close, so thank you so much as always!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
事務所がね、違うのにもうこんなに仲良くなれるなんて、もうめっちゃ嬉しいし、
Even though we're from different agencies, being this close makes me so happy,
泣いちゃうよー
I'm gonna cry~
いつも水宮に元気もらって、支えてもらってます！
and Mizumiya always gives me energy and support!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
これからもずっと友達！
Let's be friends forever!
友達！
Friends!
いっぱい遊んで、いっぱい楽しいことしていこうねー！大好きだよー！
Let's hang out a lot and do lots of fun things! Love you!
いっぱい遊ぼー！
Let's play lots!
それでは、紫刈湖でしたー！このあともライブ楽しんでね、がんばれー！
Well then, that was Shigariko! Enjoy the rest of the live show, you got this!
ありがとーーー！
Thank you so much!
うわはははは！
Wahahaha!
ということで、紫刈湖からメッセージが来ました！ありがとう、紫刈湖！
And so, that was a message from Shigariko! Thank you, Shigariko!
こっちにいるかな？ありがとう、紫刈湖ー！
Are you over there? Thank you, Shigariko-!
いや、そう、今回はね、ちょっとスケジュールが合わなくて、
Yeah, unfortunately our schedules didn't match up this time,
ちょっとリコの3Dにはね、ちょっと呼んでもらって一緒に踊ったんですけど、
she invited me to her 3D live and we danced together before,
ちょっとすうのライブでは今回は踊れなかったけど、いつか一緒にまた踊ろうな！
but we couldn't dance at Su's live this time. Let's dance together again someday!
ありがとね、リコ！水宮、頑張るよ！
Thank you, Riko! Mizumiya will do her best!
応援してもらったし、ちょっと次の曲に行こうかな！
Now that I've been cheered on, let's head to the next song!
ちょっと次はゲストパートだから、誰が来るのかな？
The next part features guests, so who could be coming?
この後もまだまだ続きます！
There's still plenty more to come!
そしてなんか告知もあるかもしれないので、
And there might be some announcements too,
最後まで楽しんでねーー！
so please enjoy until the very end!
[おこちゃま戦争 / 作詞: れをる 作曲: ギガ]
[Childish War / Lyrics: Reol / Music: Giga]
昔々の そのまた昔
Once upon a time, long, long ago,
とある貴族の 仲良しな兄弟
there were very close siblings of a noble family.
（以下略称）
(And so forth...)
「ちゃんとやれ！」
"Do it right!"
じいやが呼ぶ 席につけ
The butler calls, take your seats,
よーいドン！
ready, go!
ナイフとフォークで 応戦いたしますの
We shall fight back with knife and fork!
だって僕らは ブルジョアの
After all, we are bourgeois,
立派な 立派な 貴族様なんですの
splendid, splendid nobles!
ひれ伏せ愚民 君との違いを
Bow down, peasants! The difference between us,
ヴァイヴァイスロイ 見せてやるぜ
I'll show you what a viceroy is!
おい まてまて また勝手にそんな
Hey, wait, wait, taking liberties again,
見抜けるような ハッタリかまして
pulling such see-through bluffs!
はーい はーい はい はい
Yes, yes, okay, okay,
お兄様の仰せのままに（笑）
as my dear brother commands! (lol)
あー むかつくぜ！ まーじ むかつくぜ！
Ah, so frustrating! Seriously so frustrating!
兄に対して 生意気な態度
Such a cheeky attitude toward your older brother!
鬨の声 ゴングを鳴らせ
Battle cry, ring the gong!
ケンカ勃発で 宣戦布告
A fight breaks out, declaration of war!
悪戯して 悪ノリして
Playing pranks, getting carried away,
ほら ほら 煽ってく Style で
come on, come on, provoking in style!
“大安売り” 買っちゃったら
If you buy into this "huge bargain sale",
毎度ありがとうで 君の負け！
thank you for your business, and it's your loss!
（っしゃあ！）
(All right!)
すっぱい引き出しと 煽り合いの駆け引きでキメる
Settling it with sour tricks and provocative bargaining!
兄の威厳見せるため罵倒する 火花散る散る両者の目と目
Hurling abuse to show brotherly dignity, sparks fly between our eyes!
俺を誰だと思ってんだ くらえ！おれさまが ルールブック
Who do you think I am? Take this! I am the rulebook!
へたれじゃない！ 言ってない！ ちょっと勇気が足りないだけ！
I'm not a wimp! I didn't say that! Just lacking a little courage!
さあさあ みなさん お手を拝借
Come on everyone, lend us your applause!
当たり前だろ 余裕しゃくしゃく
Naturally, completely composed!
生まれながらにして チート
Born as a total cheat!
やべえ 煌めく 人生がスタート
An insane, dazzling life kicks off!
当然です 見てみな 優勝は ガ・チ・ゼ・イ
It's only natural, take a look, the winner is a hardcore player!
ハイ論破 ハイ論破 ハイ論破
Yes, debunked! Yes, debunked! Yes, debunked!
もらってくぜ Vサイン
Claiming that V-sign victory!
はーい はーい はい はい
Yes, yes, right, right!
はなまる よくできました☆
Gold star, well done!☆
あーむかつくぜ！まーじむかつくぜ！
Ah, it's so irritating! Seriously so annoying!
僕に向かって減らず口なんざ
Sassing back at me like that,
とっておきを きみに見舞え
I'll show you my special move!
報復！制裁！挑発しちゃって
Retaliation! Sanctions! Provoking you!
意地悪して 一枚上手
Being mean, staying one step ahead!
チャンスは貰ってくスタンスで
Taking every chance that comes my way,
痛恨ミス！あっちゃっちゃー
A critical blunder! Uh-oh!
お生憎様だね 君の負け
Too bad for you, you lose!
YES!
だけどキミ キミだけが
Yet you, only you...
やあっ！せいっ！うっ！
Ya! Take that! Ugh!
ボクに似合いのライバル
...are the only rival worthy of me!
とぉっ！やあっ！うっ！
Hah! Ya! Ugh!
落ちるのも 凹んでんのも
When I feel down or depressed...
調子狂わされるから
...it's because you throw me off my pace!
今宵も てめーと ヤイヤイヤイヤイ
Tonight again, I'll bicker with you: blah blah blah!
大体兄貴がいつもナヨナヨしてるから／お前がいつもひとりで暴走するから
You're always acting so wimpy! / You always run wild on your own!
僕が兄貴の分まで積極的になってるんだよ／俺が尻拭いせざるを得なくなるんだろうが
I have to take charge for your sake! / I have to clean up your mess!
今日から僕が兄ね／もう少し落ち着いてくれって
Starting today, I'm the older brother! / Just calm down a bit!
はい決定！／ああもう！うるせえ！
It's decided! / Oh, come on! Shut up!
あーむかつくぜ！まーじむかつくぜ！
Ah, it's so irritating! Seriously so annoying!
憎まれ口を お口をチャック
Shut that sassy mouth of yours, zip it!
鬨の声 ゴングを鳴らせ
Battle cry, sound the gong!
次世代エンペラーはこの俺だ！
The next-generation emperor is gonna be ME!
イタズラして 悪ノリして
Playing pranks, getting carried away,
ほら ほら 煽ってくStyleで
hey, hey, that's our provoking style!
1から100 いただきます
Taking everything from 1 to 100!
毎度ありがとうで君の負け
Thanks as always, and you lose!
まさかの 引き分け！？
An unexpected... tie?!
えーっ！？
What?!
この頃 君が纏う「躾直し」の季節の匂い
Lately, you carry the seasonal scent of "re-discipline."
淑やかな佇まいの割に 脆いそこに触れるの
Beneath that graceful demeanor, I touch your fragile spot.
あー 怒らないでdarling だって本当のことだもん
Ah, don't get mad, darling! After all, it's true.
身体ばっかデカくなって 中身はガキだよね
Only your body grew up, inside you're still a brat, right?
暴れないでdoggie 私 華奢な手だから
Don't struggle, doggy, my hands are delicate,
リードなんて気まぐれで パッと落としちゃうかも
so I might just let go of your leash on a whim.
だらしない 意気地ない ほんと君は救えない
Slovenly! Spineless! You really are beyond saving!
堕落に耽っちゃってご愁傷様
Indulging in degeneracy, my condolences!
夢がない 糧もない くせに愛は欲しいの？
No dreams! No drive! Yet you still crave love?
なら3回まわってお手から ワン
Then spin three times, give me your paw, and "woof"!
ルールールー ルットゥ トゥルルー
Lu lu lu lu-t-tu tu-lu-lu
ルーラララ ラットゥ トゥララー
Lu la la la la-t-tu tu-la-la
よーく聞いてdarling 僻み妬み人の企み この世は罠だらけ
Listen closely, darling: jealousy, envy, people's schemes—this world is full of traps.
ねぇ ずっとここにいて？
Hey, won't you stay here forever?
傅いてdoggie 生まれ持った才と脳で 全部を黙らせて
Grovel, doggy. With innate talent and brains, silencing everyone...
今日も稼いじゃう 私の前に
...and making bank again today, right in front of me:
follow or die でも餌は気分次第
follow or die—though the treats depend on my mood.
ねぇ 私を知らなかった頃の日々に戻りたい？
Hey, do you want to go back to the days before you knew me?
walk into a trap 無知なbabe 侵すdrug
walk into a trap, innocent babe, intoxicating like a drug.
もう私を知らなかった頃のキミは戻らない
You can never return to who you were before you knew me...
だらしない 意気地ない ほんと君は救えない
Slovenly, spineless, you really are beyond saving.
どこにも行けないね
There's nowhere left for you to go.
くだらない！果てしない！こんな広い世界で
Pointless! Endless! In this vast world,
私に堕ちていく君が好き！
I love watching you fall deeper for me!
夢がない 糧もない くせに愛が欲しいの！
No dreams! No drive! Yet you still crave love!
なら3回まわってお手から ワン！
Then spin three times, give me your paw, and "woof"!
ルールールー ルットゥ トゥルルー
Lu lu lu lu-t-tu tu-lu-lu
ルーラララ ラットゥ トゥララー
Lu la la la la-t-tu tu-la-la
※お書きになったそんな音楽は現在使われておりません
*Note: The music you have composed is currently not in use.
もう一度お書き直しください
Please rewrite it once more.
意味わかんねぇ！
What the hell does that even mean?!
Makes no damn sense!
どうせ誰も聞いてなんかないさ
Nobody is listening anyway.
音楽なんて全部ファッション
Music is nothing but fashion.
音符くぐって選手退場ワンナイ
Dodging the notes, the player exits—one-night stand.
どうせ何も伝えてなんかないさ
Nothing is being conveyed anyway.
何とかとっく取って売名
Scraping together whatever they can for clout,
あんな気取って置いて塞いでグッナイ
putting on airs and shutting down—good night.
どうしたって どう見たって
No matter what, however you look at it,
損したって問題渋滞
even at a loss, it's a gridlock of problems.
それでもあっちこっちそっちぼっち
Still, over here, over there, all alone,
マジZ世代 猿も欲しがる
totally Gen Z, even monkeys crave it.
パンチライン欲しいの
"I want a punchline,"
意味とかどっちだっていいよ
"I don't care what it means either way,"
歌詞とかどうでもいいので
"the lyrics don't matter at all,"
乗れるのをください
"just give me something I can groove to."
さあ皆で笑いましょう
Come on, let's all laugh together.
芸術より数の代償
Numbers over art—is that the price?
ウイルスに酷い代償
A terrible price paid to the virus.
じゃあどうすんの？それでいいんだっけ？
So what now? Was that really okay?
頭は空回り死んでいく
My head spins in circles, slowly dying.
ふざけるな！
Don't screw with me!
バイバイ バズメロディ
Bye-bye, buzz melody.
疑えよ 大概 嘘ばかり
Doubt it all, it's mostly lies anyway.
化けんな 幻想でも理想でもいい
Don't disguise yourself—illusions or ideals, both are fine.
君の歌いたかったもんはどうしたんだい？
What happened to what you wanted to sing?
無様でもオールライ 嘘じゃない
Even if it's clumsy, it's alright—it's not a lie.
お金や理想で満たす前に
Before filling yourself with money or ideals,
負けんな 覚醒せよ鼓動たちよ
don't lose, awaken, our heartbeats!
君の歌いたかったもんはどうしたんだい？
What happened to what you wanted to sing?
意味わかんねえ！
Makes no sense at all!
お掛けになったその音楽は 現在使われておりません
The music you have dialed is currently not in service.
ポップソング、ヒットソングを聴いて もう一度お掛け直しください
Please listen to pop songs and hit songs, then try dialing again.
ああ、もうハイカラサッカーばっか
Ah, seriously, nothing but trendy suckers.
しゃらくさいわ、はあ…
So annoying, sigh...
どいつもこいつもそいつもあいつも
This one, that one, that guy, this guy...
意味わかんねえ！
Makes no sense at all!
どうしたって どう見たって
No matter what, however you look at it,
損したって問題渋滞
even at a loss, it's a gridlock of problems.
それでもあっちこっちそっちぼっち
Still, over here, over there, all alone,
マジZ世代 猿も欲しがる
totally Gen Z, even monkeys crave it.
パンチライン欲しいの
"I want a punchline,"
意味とかどっちだっていいよ
"I don't care what it means either way,"
歌詞とかどうでもいいので
"the lyrics don't matter at all,"
伸びるのをください
"just give me something that goes viral."
さあ皆で笑いましょう
Come on, let's all laugh together.
芸術より数なんでしょう？
It's all about the numbers over art, right?
ウイルスに酷い代償
A terrible price paid to the virus.
じゃあどうすんの？それでいいんだっけ？
So what now? Was that really okay?
頭は空回り死んでいく
My head spins in circles, slowly dying.
ふざけるな！
Don't screw with me!
バイバイ バズメロディ
Bye-bye, buzz melody.
疑えよ 大概 嘘ばかり
Doubt it all, it's mostly lies anyway.
化けんな 幻想でも理想でもいい
Don't disguise yourself—illusions or ideals, both are fine.
君の歌いたかったもんはどうしたんだい？
What happened to what you wanted to sing?
このままじゃ到底 終われない
We can't possibly end it like this.
欲しいのはきっとお金じゃない
What we want surely isn't money.
負けんな 覚醒せよ鼓動たちよ
Don't lose, awaken, our heartbeats!
君の歌いたかったものがきっとあるんだ
There's surely something you wanted to sing.
ふざけるな…
Don't screw with me...
ふざけるな！バイバイ バズメロディ
Don't screw with me! Bye-bye, buzz melody.
疑えよ 大概 嘘ばかり
Doubt it all, it's mostly lies anyway.
化けんな 幻想でも理想でもいい
Don't disguise yourself—illusions or ideals, both are fine.
君の歌いたかったもんはどうしたんだい？
What happened to what you wanted to sing?
無様でもオールライ 嘘じゃない
Even if it's clumsy, it's alright—it's not a lie.
お金や理想で満たす前に
Before filling yourself with money or ideals,
負けんな 覚醒せよ鼓動たちよ
don't lose, awaken, our heartbeats!
僕の伝えたかったもんはどうしたんだい？
What happened to what I wanted to convey?
意味わかんねえ！
Makes no sense at all!
意味わかんねえよ！
It makes no damn sense!
Oh...
意味わかんねえ！
Makes no sense at all!
せーの！
Ready, set...
沙花叉、お誕生日おめでとーー！
Sakamata, happy birthday--!
ありがとーー！
Thank you so much--!
おめでとー！やったー！
Congrats! Woohoo!
何歳になったわけ？
So how old did you turn?
20歳バージョン2！
20 years old, version 2!
おー！いいね！バージョン2！
Ooh! Nice! Version 2!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
ちょっとみんなせっかく来てくれ…あっ…
Guys, thank you so much for coming... Ah...
おい！大丈夫？倒れてる！
Hey! Are you okay? She collapsed!
あんた違うでしょ！何番前や？
You're not the one! Whose turn was that?
だけど、今日の主役ですから、水生生物は！
But hey, the aquatic creature is today's star!
じゃあみんなに一言言ってね、去ってもらおうかなって！
So I figured everyone could say a few words before heading off!
1人ずつ来なよ、ほら。スムーズにほら、愛をね。
Come up one by one, come on. Smoothly share some love.
一言愛をね！一言言いに来なよ、ほら。
A quick word of love! Come say a few words, go on.
じゃあ誰から？ほら、嫌…
Alright, who's first? Look, if you don't...
うん… ママだよ。
Yeah... It's your mama.
おめでと！ありがと！
Congrats! Thank you!
何それ？！何この動き？！何あいつ！
What is that?! What's with that move?! What is she doing?!
もう、ほら、ちゃんときなよ！
Geez, come on, do it properly!
はいはい。変な人いて怖かったでしょ？
Okay, okay. That weird person was scary, wasn't she?
なんかおかしくね？
Isn't something off here?
ママよ。
I'm your mama.
あー違うよ！違う、違う！
Ah, no, that's wrong! No, no!
押し戻した！おい！ちょっと待って！
She pushed her back! Hey! Wait a sec!
俺がママだ！俺がママだ！
I'm the mama! I'm the mama!
待って、ちょっと待って！あの、別にうちら芸人じゃないのよ！
Wait, hold on a second! Look, we're not comedians!
手招きしてたからびびった。
You were beckoning, so it startled me.
はい！これからもクロヱお姉ちゃんに頼ってね〜！
Yes! Rely on big sis Chloe from now on too, okay~?
お姉ちゃんだと思ってるの？本当に。
Do you honestly think you're my big sister?
おかしい！おかしいよ！
That's crazy! That's so uncalled for!
ほら、ちゃんと愛をね！最後愛を！スムーズにね！
Come on, give some love properly! Love at the end! Smoothly!
いや、でも、うちらの、ズッ友の仲やんか。
Well, but aren't we lifelong besties?
そうね！
That's right!
だから、せーのって言ったら…
So, when I say "Ready, set..."
分かるよな？
You know what to do, right?
分かった。行くよ？
Got it. Here we go!
せーの、スリー、ツー、ワン！
Ready, set... Three, two, one!
待って！待って！
Wait! Hold on!
全然違う！
You're completely out of sync!
いや、合わせて！
No, match with me!
合わせて！
Match with me!
せーの、スリー・サイコー！
Ready, set... Three, awesome!
ハート作って！これでいいんだよ！
Make a heart! Like this is fine!
大丈夫？届いてる？
Is this okay? Are we reaching you?
じゃあね、みんな！ありがとう！
See ya, everyone! Thank you!
ありがとう！頑張って！応援してるよ！
Thank you! Good luck! We're rooting for you!
ママ、良かったよ！
Mama, you were great!
よしよしよし...
There, there, there...
ありがとう！バイバーイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
頑張れー！さいならー！
Do your best! Farewell!
なんかうるさかったな。
That was kinda noisy...
頑張るか。よし。
Alright, let's do this. Okay!
くだらない愛の結果で
As the outcome of a pointless love,
僕らは生まれ落ちて
we were born into this world,
呼吸さえ強いられているけど
forced even to keep breathing, but...
綺麗な言葉並べて
Lining up pretty words,
醜さに蓋をして
putting a lid over the ugliness,
自分を愛せないままだな
I still can't bring myself to love who I am...
ずっと
Not for the longest time.
波に名前をつけること、僕らの呼吸に終わりがあること。
[Song: Naming the Waves, Our Breathing Having an End - Tatsuya Kitani]
くだらない嘘を言う度
Every time a pointless lie is told,
青い色 こぼれ落ちた
shades of blue came spilling down,
硝子の瞳が綺麗で
and those glassy eyes were so beautiful.
君のその瞼の様に
Just like those eyelids of yours,
優しい人になってさ
if I could become a kind person,
そんな僕を愛したいんだよ
I would want to love that version of myself.
私の呼吸に終わりがあること
Knowing that there is an end to my breath,
君の声を覚えている
I still remember your voice.
生まれては消えていくこと
Being born only to fade away,
それだけを繰り返している
repeating that over and over again.
僕らがもし また会えたらだなんて
"What if we could meet again?"
思ってた
I used to think.
生まれては消えて行くだけの
Merely being born only to fade away,
青白い波に名前をつけることに
giving a name to these pale blue waves...
意味は無かったのかな、なんてさ
Was there truly no meaning to it at all?
他愛ない急ぎ足見た
I watched trivial, hurried footsteps,
積み木で遊んでいる
playing with building blocks,
崩れるその日を待ってる
waiting for the day they collapse.
澄み切った夜の静寂
In the crystal-clear silence of the night,
君の頬の赤い色で
with the rosy flush on your cheeks,
もうすぐ桜が咲くだろう
the cherry blossoms will surely bloom soon.
僕らの呼吸に意味がなくても
Even if there is no meaning to our breathing,
二人はまた恋をする
the two of us will fall in love once more.
生まれては消えていくこと
Being born only to fade away,
それだけを繰り返している
repeating that over and over again.
そして君も 夜の海に帰って行くんだろう
And you too will likely return to the night sea.
生まれては消えて行くだけの
Merely being born only to fade away,
青白い波に名前をつけることに
giving a name to these pale blue waves...
囚われている
I am still trapped by it.
覚えているかな
Do you remember?
いつかの春の朝に
On a spring morning back then,
桜の木の下で
under the cherry blossom tree,
約束したこと
what we promised each other.
思い出も 君の名前も
Both the memories and your name,
いつの日か失ってしまって
one day I will lose them all,
僕もいつか この海と一つになるんだろう
and I too will someday become one with this sea.
君のいない冬の空気が
As the winter air without you
僕の頬を刺す その痛みさえ
stings my cheek, even that pain
愛していたい
is something I want to love.
生まれては消えていくこと
Being born only to fade away,
それだけを繰り返している
repeating that over and over again.
僕らがもし また会えたらだなんて
"What if we could meet again?"
思ってた
I used to think.
生まれては消えて行くだけの
Merely being born only to fade away,
青白い波に名前をつけることに
giving a name to these pale blue waves...
意味は無かったのかな
Was there truly no meaning to it at all?
こうして冬が終わって
And like this, winter comes to an end,
青い春が来る
and a blue spring arrives.
UNHAPPY? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? O troubled child of man,
UNLUCKY? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? Even you non-human beings,
BE HAPPY! 弛まず目指せよ
Be happy! Strive tirelessly for it,
生きているんだし
after all, you're alive.
目を逸らした過去も
The past you averted your eyes from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future too—
カウンセリング
counseling!
やれやれ 古今東西 ピースピース
Good grief, everywhere and through all time, peace peace!
UNHAPPY
UNLUCKY
BE HAPPY!
UNDEAD
ね、ね、ね、ね 何だかどうして 戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Hey, hey, hey, hey, why does it somehow feel like I'm fighting?
触れられない (触れたくもない) 過去の自分自分自分自分と
With the past me, me, me, me, untouchable (and unwanted to touch).
もうとっくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
Facing off against a transparent ghost that died long ago,
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
deep within childish, painful memories.
残念? もう居ないのに
Regret? Even though they're already gone...
あれ? そっちが良い? アイロニーね
Huh? That's better? How ironic.
透かされているのは現在の自分?
Is the one being seen through my present self?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル YES
Nonsense, an indelible label, yes!
要はコンプレックス 取り憑かれているみたい
In short, a complex—it's like I'm possessed.
巻き付いたまま まだ離れない
Still wrapped around me, refusing to let go,
在りし日の自分
the self from days gone by.
UNDEAD
死んじゃない お前とお前の連鎖
Not dead yet—a chain connecting you with yourself.
生きていることとは 変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to keep on changing!
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't settle for unhappiness and be satisfied!
幸せになろうとしないなんて 卑怯だ
Not even trying to become happy is just cowardly!
この世 この世は 奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a bizarre, bizarre fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Will an ogre or a serpent appear next?
出会って遭って やっと始まる物語
Encountering and facing them, the story finally begins!
さあ人か 化物か
Now, is it human or a monster?
閑話休題 ピースピース
Putting that aside, peace peace!
Past & Future can't change the past
Past and future, can't change the past!
Past & Future run for the future
Past and future, run for the future!
カットイン
Cut in!
何だかどうして 未来になんぞ 何の希望もない 期待出来ない ような気がして
For some reason, it feels like there's no hope or expectation for the future...
もう随分生きている
I've lived for quite a while now,
既視感とテンプレで食傷 素敵な出来事の気配もない
fed up with deja vu and clichés, with no sign of anything wonderful happening.
残念
Disappointing.
積んだ経験の因果 形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
The karma of accumulated experience, formal myths and boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ 飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった なんて
In short, I just want excitement—saying I'm bored of it or used to it...
整っていくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス 蓋されていくみたい
Tidy guidelines and increasing compliance—it feels like a lid is being put on.
吸い尽くして
Draining it all dry,
あれも これも どれも 同じ味がする
that, this, whatever it is—they all taste the same.
UNDEAD
死んじゃない お前とお前の連鎖
Not dead yet—a chain connecting you with yourself.
何時の世も 過去も未来も 現在にあるんだ
In every era, the past and the future exist right now in the present!
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill your living life with honest devotion,
目指せハッピーエンド
and aim for a happy ending!
UNDEAD
死んじゃない お前に言っているんだ
Not dead yet—I'm talking to you!
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人で在れ
Don't give up on happiness—stay human!
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
If you just get used to suffering and endure it,
死んでいるも同然 屍のアンデッド
you might as well be dead—a corpse, undead!
UNHAPPY? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? O troubled child of man,
UNLUCKY? 人成らざる者のも
Unlucky? Even you non-human beings,
BE HAPPY! 弛まず目指せよ 生きているんだろ
Be happy! Strive tirelessly for it—you're alive, aren't you?
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも そう全部全部お前だ
Drowning in misfortune or becoming happy—yes, it's all entirely up to you!
古今東西 一切合切 森羅万象 ピースピース
Everywhere and through all time, everything and all creation, peace peace!
Past & Future can't change the past
Past and future, can't change the past!
Past & Future run for the future
Past and future, run for the future!
人の在る所に何時も憂い事
Wherever people are, there are always worries.
生き抜け この化物ばかりの物語
Survive this story full of nothing but monsters!
ちょっとヤンチャで 見事元気な
A bit mischievous and wonderfully energetic,
キラッとスマイル アイドル
a sparkling-smile idol!
毎日をもっと 楽しくしたいの
I want to make every day more fun!
ドン・ウォーリー・ウィズ・アドベンチャー
Don't worry, with adventure!
ヒラヒラスカートも
Even a fluttering skirt,
ちゃんと着こなせるんだよ
I can pull off wearing it properly!
だからもっともっと 好きになってもいいよ
So it's okay to fall in love with me more and more!
一緒に 大空に飛び立とう
Let's take off into the vast sky together!
光るスターライト 眩しい輝きの中の 強い煌めき
Shining starlight, an intense glitter amidst the dazzling radiance!
君に届いているかな
I wonder if it's reaching you?
1mmでも伝わればいいな
If even just a millimeter gets through, that'd be great!
チャージ チャレンジ 全力で汗かく 頑張る君へ
Charge, challenge! To you giving it your all, sweating and doing your best,
1番乗りのスマイルを
here's the very first smile for you!
…ける スバルch
...Subaru ch!
everyday night & day みんなで！
Every day, night & day, all together!
ブルーな気持ちに ズバッと駆けつけ
Rushing right over to your blue mood,
お助けしちゃうヒーロー！
I'm a hero who comes to the rescue!
弱いハートじゃ いられないから
Because I can't afford to have a weak heart,
つよつよでいきましょー！
let's go super strong!
ハラハラな水着で
In thrilling swimsuits,
ドキドキのときめき time
it's heart-pounding, thrilling time...
いつでもおいでよ 一年中パラダイス
Come by anytime, it's paradise all year round!
ドカンと 曇り空 吹き飛ばそう
Let's blow away the cloudy skies with a bang!
あがれ！ スターマイン どんな暗闇の中も
Soar high, starmine! No matter how deep the darkness,
眩しく照らす
it shines brightly.
キミに見つけてもらえた
Just that you found me,
それだけでもう運命なんだ
is already fate enough.
もっとずーっと道は続いてく
The road keeps going on and on,
夢に向かって
toward our dreams.
一緒に来てくれるかな？
Will you come along with us?
その手とって走れ
Take that hand and run,
つれていくよ みんなで！
we'll take you along, all together!
ささやく 言葉は 恥ずかしいけれど
Whispering these words is embarrassing, but
(こっそり、ね)
(Secretly, okay?)
伝えたい想い
The feelings I want to share...
今なら言える (あのね ドキドキ…)
I can say them now (You know, my heart is racing...)
キミのエールがチカラになるよ
Your cheers give me strength!
いつも元気を分けてくれて
Thank you for always sharing your energy with me.
頑張っていけるんだ 笑って過ごせるんだ
I can keep giving my best, I can live smiling,
本当に ありがとうの気持ちを
these feelings of gratitude from the bottom of my heart...
歌え！ star light どんな輝きの中も
Sing out, star light! Amidst all kinds of radiance,
強いキラメキ
a powerful shimmer.
キミに届いているかな？
Is it reaching you?
1ミリでも伝われ fight oh！
Even if just one millimeter, let it reach! Fight oh!
もっとずーっと道は続いてく
The road keeps going on and on,
夢に向かって
toward our dreams.
一緒に来てくれるかな？
Will you come along with us?
その手とって走れ
Take that hand and run,
つれていくよ みんなで！
we'll take you along, all together!
キミと駆ける スバル！
Subaru, dashing with you!
スバル先輩ありがとうございましたー！家宝にします！
Subaru-senpai, thank you so much! I'll treasure this as a family heirloom!
コボ頑張れー！
Kobo, do your best!
お誕生日おめでとおおお！
Happy birthdayyyy!
誰かのための痛み
Pain for someone else's sake?
僕の願い やがて散り散り
My wish, eventually scattered.
イス取りゲームみたい
Like a game of musical chairs,
それでも 息をしていくしかない
still, I have no choice but to keep breathing.
まだ聞こえるか？ とっくのとうに詰まった呼吸
Can you still hear it? Breath choked up long ago.
関係ない うるせえわ 自分だけが聞こえてる
Doesn't matter, shut up! Only I can hear it.
安定なんて捨てた もう全てを振り切るスピードで
I threw away stability, now at a speed that shakes off everything!
その瞬間まで足掻いて
Struggling until that very moment,
ただ脳絞って 今見えるとこまで
just racking my brain, as far as I can see right now.
この瞬間を飲み干して また踊って
Drink down this moment and dance again,
見たことないもの見せて
show me something I've never seen before.
君の代わりはいない
"There's no replacement for you."
もし誰かが否定しても
Even if someone denies it,
僕の代わりはいない
there's no replacement for me.
違ぐことない 僕の目覚まし
Without a doubt, my awakening.
誰かの祈る手を払った痛み どこから漂う悪意の兆し
The pain of brushing off a praying hand, signs of malice drifting from somewhere.
正しさに息を潜めた怒り それすらも僕に残った光
Anger holding its breath in righteousness, even that is a light left in me.
誰彼の熱を奪う感覚 逃げる気はとうにないぜ全く
The sensation of stealing anyone and everyone's heat, I've no intention to run away, none at all.
この手が震えるほどの錯覚が 起こした摩擦
The friction caused by an illusion so strong it makes this hand tremble.
まだ見えてるか？ とっくにスポットライトを奪った
Can you still see it? I snatched the spotlight long ago.
関係ない うるせえわ 自分だけに聞かせている
Doesn't matter, shut up! I'm only letting myself hear it.
安定なんてやめだ もう全てを振り切るスピードで
Forget about stability! Now at a speed that shakes off everything!
その瞬間だけ足掻いたって意味ないぜ
Struggling only for that moment is meaningless.
今見えるとこまで
As far as I can see right now.
第六感で引き合って また踊って
Drawn together by a sixth sense, dance again,
見たことないものを見せて
show me something I've never seen before.
今をぶち抜いて！
Pierce through the now!
もうノンストップで 脳すり切れるまで
Already nonstop, until the brain wears down!
この瞬間を飲み干して また踊って
Drink down this moment and dance again,
見たことないもの見せて
show me something I've never seen before.
さあ この瞬間を見逃して
Now, miss this moment,
また怒って 見たことないもの見せて
and get angry again, show me something never seen before.
連れて行かれるように
As if being led away,
踏み出した 暗い街へ
I stepped out into the dark streets.
Tell me what you need 追った
Tell me what you need, the back I chased
背中は黒く染まってた
was dyed in pitch black.
Wait, hold up 悪党？ それとも正義？ Huh?
Wait, hold up. A villain? Or justice? Huh?
見返り探す馬鹿みたい (What?)
Searching for a reward like an idiot (What?)
目の前の問題はいつも後回しでもいいじゃん
It's fine to always put off the problems in front of us, right?
人生の意味 結局何？
What is the meaning of life anyway?
不安定な日々に裏返る声
A voice turning inside out in unstable days.
あれこれ言ってる間に
While saying this and that,
姿消し去った君は誰？ (誰？)
who are you who disappeared? (Who?)
曖昧な世界が変わった
The ambiguous world changed
あの日 派手に響かせた
that day I let my voice echo out flashily.
声がまた今も鳴り止まない
That voice still won't stop ringing out.
紅の夜に 心奪われて
My heart was stolen by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に
and in this helpless emotion,
君を映してた
I was reflecting you.
増えていく影を追い
Chasing the multiplying shadows,
気づけば遠い街で
before I knew it, I was in a distant town.
引き返し元通りになるのには
To turn back and return to how it was
もう遅かった
was already too late.
Wait, hold up now SOS 逃げ道がないの？
Wait, hold up now. SOS, is there no escape?
え、ちょっと待って How is it my fault?
Wait, hold on. How is it my fault?
Left to the right step からの Get down に見せかけて clap
Left to the right step, then faking a get down into a clap.
格好つけて立場を問うて
Acting cool and questioning your standing,
助けてやって何その態度
I helped you out, so what's with that attitude?
不満の中で生まれる依存症
An addiction born from dissatisfaction,
垣間見えるのは愛
what's glimpsed through is love.
退屈な世界が変わった
The boring world changed
あの日 派手に響かせた
that day I let my voice echo out flashily.
声がまた今も鳴り止まない
That voice still won't stop ringing out.
紅の夜に 心奪われて
My heart was stolen by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に
and in this helpless emotion,
君を映してた
I was reflecting you.
このどうしようもない感情に
In this helpless emotion,
君を映してた
I was reflecting you.
No, no, no, oh...
肺 肺 腹から声出して
Yeah, yeah, yell it from your gut!
そんなんじゃ痛い目に遭いまっせ
Keep that up and you're in for a world of hurt.
勝敗かけた歌合戦
A sing-off with victory on the line,
枯れそうな声でまだ 歌うのさ
with a voice on the verge of dying, I'll keep singing!
ド派手に響かせた
Echoing out in super flashy style,
声がまた今も鳴り止まない
that voice still won't stop ringing out.
紅の夜に 心奪われて
My heart was stolen by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に
and in this helpless emotion,
君を映してた
I was reflecting you.
Oh, no, no, no, yeah...
紅の夜に 心奪われて
My heart was stolen by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に
and in this helpless emotion,
君を映してた
I was reflecting you.
All eyes, all eyes on me, on, on
All eyes, all eyes on me
関係、探って
Gauging our relationship,
嗚呼 ごめんねって意味がないね
saying "ah, sorry" is completely meaningless.
満ち足りない そっと暴いて
It's not enough; gently expose it.
二重で被る面相
A double-layered facial mask,
優しい言葉並べて
lining up gentle words,
ふたり お揃いに甘えて
the two of us indulging together.
演じて見せてるのは誰のために
Who am I putting on this act for?
ただ 泣いたように笑っていたんだ
I was simply smiling as if I were crying.
All eyes on me 偽りの Deepfaker
All eyes on me, a counterfeit deepfaker.
愛なんてわかっちゃいないんだ
I don't understand love at all.
All eyes on me いつの間にか Deepfaker
All eyes on me, becoming a deepfaker before I knew it.
All eyes, all eyes on me, on me, on me Faker
All eyes, all eyes on me, Deep Faker
重ね重ねお詫びします
I apologize profusely again and again,
気持ちのない口癖
an insincere catchphrase.
優しさに狡さも吐き違えて
Mistaking kindness for slyness,
重ね重ね
layer upon layer,
た嘘の吐息だけで満たされるマスク
a mask filled only with the breath of accumulated lies.
まだ二重で縛っている 心の中 散々取り繕っている
Still binding it twofold, endlessly patching things up inside my heart.
本当の顔は
Who is my real face for...
誰のためで
...and for whose sake?
だんだん苦しくなるね
It's gradually getting painful.
お揃いの甘えの前借り
Borrowing matched pampering in advance,
ただ泣いてないで笑っていたいよ
I just want to smile without crying.
All eyes on me いつまでも Feel flavor
All eyes on me, feel flavor forever.
Iなんてわかっちゃいないんだ
I don't understand what "I" even means.
All eyes on me いつの日にか Deepfaker
All eyes on me, someday a deepfaker.
脱いでみたい
I want to take it off,
演技でもないなら
if it's not just an act.
それまで肩寄せながら
Until then, leaning shoulder to shoulder,
胸に秘めている Deepfaker
keeping it hidden inside my heart, deepfaker.
まだ泣いたように笑っていたんだ
I was still smiling as if I were crying.
All eyes on me 偽りの Deepfaker
All eyes on me, a counterfeit deepfaker.
Iなんてわかっちゃいないんだ
I don't understand what "I" even means.
All eyes on me いつのまにか Deepfaker
All eyes on me, before I knew it, a deepfaker.
All eyes, all eyes on me, on- on- on me, faker
All eyes, all eyes on me, dee- dee- deep, deep faker
みんな、どうでしたか〜？
How was that, everyone?
いやぁ〜、今回はですね、あのハウスにね、初めて挑戦したんですけれども
Well, this time, I took on house dance for the very first time, but...
あの2ヶ月で、あの詰め込んで、踊れてましたか〜？
...having crammed it all in two months, did I dance well?
いや、「めっちゃ頑張った」ってコメントが返してくれてるんだろうなぁ〜。
Man, I'm sure people are commenting things like "You worked so hard!"
いやはや。でね、あの『波に名前をつけること、僕らの呼吸に終わりがあること。』っていう曲では
Goodness. And you know, in the song "Naming the Waves, Our Breathing Having an End",
リフトをしたり、あのくるくるね、回って、あれも初めてやりました！
we did lifts and spun around and around—that was my first time doing that too!
驚いてたら嬉しいなぁ〜。
I'd be so happy if you were surprised!
いや、ゲストのね、白石先輩、ハジタンともイケイケに踊って、
Also, I danced energetically with my guests, Shiraishi-senpai and Hajitan,
スバル先輩とは、憧れのスバル先輩と2人きりでドキドキタイムもしちゃったり、
and with Subaru-senpai—my idol Subaru-senpai—the two of us had a heart-pounding time together,
ロボ子と、いろは先輩となでちゃんとはね、もう対決しまくって、
and with Roboco, Iroha-senpai, and Nade-chan, we had tons of showdowns,
ローズセブンとマリンちゃんは可愛く、FGとはかっこよく、
and Rose Seven and Marine-chan were cute, FG was cool...
いやぁ、ゲストパートもたくさんね、素晴らしいのがあったんじゃないでしょうか〜！
Man, there were so many wonderful moments in the guest segments, weren't there?!
ということで、皆さん、何か忘れてませんか〜？
And so... everyone, aren't you forgetting something?
ね、皆さん。ちょっと水海あの休憩タイムもね、もうそろそろ終わらないといけない。
Hey, everyone. Minamiya's break time has to wrap up soon too.
よし、立つか〜。
Alright, time to stand up.
はい、ということで、なんとですね、こんな感じで言うのも何ですが、
Okay! So, amazingly enough, though it might be a bit sudden to say it like this...
新曲が…出ます！イェーイ！
A new song... is coming out! Yay!!
初のオリジナル楽曲！ふっふっふっふ！
My very first original song! Hehehehe!
あ、やばい、体が疲れた。よいしょ、よいしょ。
Ah, oh no, my body is tired. Oof, oof.
はい、ということで、えっと作詞・作曲・編曲はサトダユーリさんに作ってもらいました！
Yes! So, Satoda Yuri-san handled the lyrics, composition, and arrangement!
ありがとトントンパフパフ！トントンパフパフ〜！
Thank you, ton-ton puff-puff! Ton-ton puff-puff~!
はい！この後、すぐMV公開がね、この配信が終わった後あるのですが、
Yes! Right after this stream ends, the MV premiere will take place,
リダイレクトで飛びます！
and it'll redirect you right over!
そして、デジタルリリースは今日の0時からなので、たくさん聴いてくれると嬉しいです！
And the digital release is tonight from midnight, so I'd love it if you listen to it a lot!
じゃあ、ちょっと早速なんですけど、その新曲をお披露目しちゃおうかな！
Well then, right away, shall I debut that new song?!
いや、どんな楽曲なんだろうな〜。気になるな〜。どんな楽曲なんだろう。行きます！
What kind of song could it be? So exciting! What could it be? Here we go!
うみゃうにゃはっぴーらいふ
[Song: Umya Unya Happy Life]
うみゃうみゃ！ うみゃうみゃ！
Umya umya! Umya umya!
うにゃうにゃ！ うにゃうにゃ！
Unya unya! Unya unya!
うみゃうみゃ！ うにゃうにゃ！
Umya umya! Unya unya!
ぐるるん？ きゅるるん？
Gururun? Kyururun?
あ〜 そろそろ ごはんの時間かな？
Ah~ Is it almost mealtime?
あ、でも でも、やっぱ やっぱ
Ah, but, but... as expected,
家から 一歩も 出たくな〜いっ！！
I don't wanna take a single step outside!!
こんな 時は そうだ！
At times like this, I know!
飯テロの 動画！
Food-porn videos!
「説明しよう！ 極限まで お腹を 空かし 美味しく いただくのだ！」
"Allow me to explain! Starve yourself to the limit, and eat deliciously!"
めんどい めんどい マジ めんどいわ
Such a pain, such a pain, seriously such a pain!
けっきょく ぐだぐだ 時間 溶けたわ
In the end, I just dawdled and wasted time!
ぴろりん ぴろりん 5回目 アラーム
Pirorin, pirorin, 5th alarm ringing!
コンビニ いこー
Let's go to the convenience store~
わちゃわちゃ はちゃめちゃ 奇想天外
Chaotic, crazy, and fantastic!
ドタバタ てんやわんや 見逃せない
Slapstick and hectic, don't miss it!
ピンチだって ちょちょいのちょいで
Even when in a pinch, in just a snap,
てやっ！ てやっ
Te-ya! Te-ya!
そりゃっ そりゃっ！
So-rya! So-rya!
万事解決☆
Everything's solved☆
うみゃうみゃ うにゃうにゃ
Umya umya, unya unya,
おいしくなあれ☆
become delicious☆
あれも これも ぜんぶ 食べたいの (ちょーだい！)
I wanna eat this, that, everything! (Gimme!)
ぱくぱく うみゃうみゃ ハピネス ライフ
Munch munch, umya umya, happiness life!
食べて 寝て 遊んで また 食べる (おーいぇー！)
Eat, sleep, play, and eat again! (Oh yeah!)
ぺこぺこ ぺこぺこ はらぺこじゃ (じゃ？)
Starving, starving, 'cause I'm so hungry! (Huh?)
うみゃうみゃうみゃ うまくいきません (ぶー！ ぶー！)
Umya-umya-umya, things won't go well! (Boo! Boo!)
ひとまず ごはんを
For now, feed me...
おなか いっぱい
...until my tummy is full!
あ〜いい天気〜
Ah, such nice weather~
あの雲ソフトクリームみたい！
That cloud looks like soft serve!
あ、あっちはわたがし！
Ah, that one's cotton candy!
雲ってふわふわで美味しそう…
Clouds look so fluffy and delicious...
人生で1回は食べてみたいよね〜
I'd love to try eating one at least once in my life~
じゃない！！
...Wait, no!!
しんどいしんどい まじしんどいわ
So exhausted, so exhausted, seriously so exhausted
現実逃避 何度もしちゃうわ
I keep escaping from reality over and over
妄想 空想 頭が暴走
Delusions, daydreaming, my head's running wild
カツオ食べたーい！！！
I wanna eat bonito fish!!!
だらだら ぐうたら 怠惰全開
Lazing around, slacking off, pure laziness full throttle
ネガティブ思考も ご愛敬です！
Even negative thoughts are part of my charm!
世界だってぽっぽいのぽいで
Tossing the whole world aside like trash,
えいやっ！ えいやっ とりゃっ とりゃっ
Eiya! Eiya! Torya! Torya!
ねじ伏せちゃうぞ☆
I'll pin it right down☆
うみゃ うみゃ うにゃ うにゃ
Umya umya unya unya
お腹すいたら 突撃となりの晩ごはん
When I get hungry, I'll raid next door for dinner
（ちょーだい！）
(Give me some!)
ぱくぱく うみゃうみゃ しあわせタイム
Munching away, umya umya, happy time
主に食欲で生きてます
I'm practically powered by appetite alone
（おーいえー！）
(Oh yeah!)
だからどうかお願い
So pretty please, I beg of you
このおなかを満たして神様！
God, fill this tummy of mine!
たべたーい
I wanna eat~
ねてたーい
I wanna sleep~
むずかしいことは 何も考えたくない
I don't wanna think about anything complicated
「あとあと、みんなでお菓子パーティもしたーい！！」
"And and, I also wanna have a sweets party with everyone!!"
うみゃ うみゃ うにゃ うにゃ
Umya umya unya unya
おいしくなあれ☆
Turn out delicious☆
あれもこれも ぜんぶ食べたいな
I wanna eat this and that and everything
（ちょーだい！）
(Give me some!)
ぱくぱく うみゃうみゃ ハピネスライフ
Munching away, umya umya, happiness life
食べて寝て遊んで また食べる
Eat, sleep, play, and eat again
（おーいえー！）
(Oh yeah!)
ぺこぺこ ぺこぺこ はらぺこじゃ
My tummy's rumbling, rumbling, so hungry
（じゃ？）
(Huh?)
うみゃうみゃうみゃ うまくいきません
Umya umya umya, things aren't going well
（ぶー！ぶー！）
(Boo! Boo!)
ひとまずごはんを お腹いっぱい
For now, let me eat food till my belly is full,
食べさせて
feed me!
まだ足りない
Still not enough!
もっと もっと 食べさせて
Feed me more, even more!
新曲、どうだった〜？
How was the new song~?
可愛かったでしょう〜？
Wasn't it super cute~?
可愛いっていうコメントがたくさん見えます！
I see so many comments saying it's cute!
ありがとね。可愛い可愛いありがとう、知ってる知ってる。
Thank you! "Cute, cute," thanks! I know, I know.
ということでね
So then,
新曲のタイトルは『うみゃうにゃはっぴーらいふ』でした〜！
the title of the new song was "Umyaunya Happy Life"~!
今回はちょっと可愛い感じにしたので
Since I went with a cute vibe this time,
次はなんかかっこいい感じにしたいな〜みたいな、まあ何も決まってないんですけどね。
I'd like to do something cool next time, though nothing is decided yet!
ということで、新曲が終わったからって帰ろうとしてない？
So, just because the new song is over, you aren't trying to leave, are you?
ねえ、なんか忘れてるよね、みんな？
Hey, aren't you guys forgetting something?
ということで、グッズーー！
And so... MERCHANDISE--!
水宮枢、誕生日記念2026のグッズを早速1つずつ見ていこう〜！
Let's check out each of the Mizumiya Su Birthday Celebration 2026 merch items right away~!
まずは、こちら〜！
First up is this~!
オーロラアクリルパネル〜！
Aurora Acrylic Panel~!
公式イラストレーターのぶくろてママに描いてもらいました。ありがとママ〜！
Drawn by my official illustrator, Bukurote-mama! Thank you, Mama~!
ふわふわのね、お部屋でお茶会みたいなね、可愛い感じになっております〜！
It turned out super cute, like having a tea party in a fluffy room~!
もうママが天才すぎるので、ぜひ買ってください〜！
Mama is just too much of a genius, so please be sure to buy one~!
2つ目は、こちら〜！
The second one is this~!
ハート型缶バッジー！
Heart-Shaped Button Badge!
ハート、ハート、ハート！
Heart, heart, heart!
こちらはね、もう可愛いお顔がドアップになって
For this one, my cute face is shown in an extreme close-up,
で、枢たぶんハート型の缶バッジは初めてなんじゃないかなと思っているので
and I think this might be my very first heart-shaped button badge,
ぜひこちらも買ってみてください〜！
so definitely be sure to grab this one too~!
3つ目が、こちら！
The third one is this!
おくるみすぅぬいぐるみ〜！
Swaddled Suu Plushie~!
こちらもね、すぅちゃんがおくるみに入っています
For this one as well, Suu-chan is all wrapped up in a swaddle!
まあなんか枢をね、結構おくるみに入れてくれてる方も見たりとかしたので
Well, I've seen quite a few people putting me into swaddles and things,
もしかしたらみんなこういうのを待っていたんじゃないかな〜と思って作りました〜！
so I thought maybe this is what everyone's been waiting for, and had it made~!
衣装はね、キービジュアルの衣装で、ちょっと小さめのぬいぐるみを作ってみました〜！
For the outfit, it's the key visual outfit, made into a slightly smaller plushie~!
4つ目は、こちら！
The fourth one is this!
れきお一推しショルダーバッグーー！
Rekio Top-Pick Shoulder Bag--!
こちらにですね、さっきのハート型のね、缶バッジとか
With this, you can put the heart-shaped button badges from earlier,
おくるみぬいぐるみが入れれるようになってま〜す！
or the swaddled plushie right inside~!
はい、天才、天才、天才！
Yep, genius, genius, genius!
ということで、こちらも一緒にぜひれきおのね、推し活のバッグに入れて
So, please put them together inside the Rekio fan-support bag,
枢をね、あの、可愛く持ってください！よろしくね〜！
and carry Suu around looking super cute! Pretty please~!
他の推し様もぜひ入れてみてね〜！
Feel free to put your other faves inside too~!
5つ目が、こちら！
The fifth one is this!
ボイス〜！
Voice Pack~!
タイトルは『すぅとお茶会』
The title is "Tea Party with Suu".
こちらはね、お家で優雅な、優雅な、優雅なアフタヌーンティーを
In this one, having an elegant, elegant, elegant afternoon tea at home,
楽しむすぅと一緒にね
enjoying it together with Suu,
いっぱい楽しんじゃおうボイスとなっております〜！
it's a voice pack where you can have tons of fun together~!
最後に、フルセット！
And finally, the Full Set!
直筆サイン入りのオリジナルカードと、ASMRボイスが付いてきま〜す！
It comes with an original card with a handwritten autograph and an ASMR voice pack~!
ちょっとね、すぅ...
It's a bit, you know, Suu...
おうちに お呼ばれしちゃったみんながね
For everyone who got invited over to my house,
ちょっと距離近めでね ASMRボイスが
there's an ASMR voice from a close distance,
こんな感じで…まあ適当なんですけど そんな感じのボイスになっております！
like this... Well, that was just off the cuff, but that's what kind of voice it is!
こちら！数量限定じゃ…ない！
This is... NOT limited in quantity!
ので 焦らずに みんなゆっくりで大丈夫です！
So don't panic, everyone can take their time!
グッズは22時1…え？ん？22時10分から販売開始です！
The merch goes on sale starting at 22:1... huh? 22:10!
直筆のサインとかもね 全部！もう何もかも数量限定じゃないので！
Even the handwritten autographs, everything! Absolutely none of it is limited in quantity,
あの すーちゃんのサインも ついてきますのでね フルセットを買ったら！
so Suu-chan's autograph will also be included if you buy the full set!
みなさん よろしくお願いします！
Please check it out, everyone!
ぜひ！買ってねー！いっぱい買ってー！
Please buy it! Buy lots of them!
はい！ということで 以上 ミニミアによるグッズ紹介でしたー！
Alright! And that concludes the merch showcase by Mini Mia!
うわっ
Whoa!
はーい！ということで ミニミアありがとうー！
All right! So, thank you, Mini Mia!
なんか結構ミスってたな まあミニミアだからね まあすーじゃないから ま 仕方ないか！
She messed up quite a bit, huh. Well, that was Mini Mia, not Suu, so I guess it can't be helped!
ということで 誕生日の3Dライブはどうだったでしょうかー？
So then, how was my birthday 3D live stream?!
憧れのホロライブに入ってから みんなにいーっぱい応援してもらって ここまで来れました！
Ever since joining Hololive, my dream agency, thanks to all your support, I was able to make it this far!
みんなに少しでもね「かっこよかった」とか「すーちゃんのこと応援しててよかった」って思ってもらえてると とっても嬉しいです！
If you felt even a bit like "that was cool" or "I'm glad I supported Suu-chan," I'd be so happy!
MVはこの後すぐ公開で リダイレクトで飛ぶので チャンネルはそのままでよろしくお願いします！
The MV premieres right after this and will automatically redirect, so please stay on this channel!
ということで みんな これからもよろしくね！ありがとうー！
So, everyone, please keep supporting me from now on! Thank you so much!
じゃあ バイバーイ！またねー！
Well then, bye-bye! See you later!
すずりすへ ずっと見守ってずっと応援してくれてありがとう！
[Letter: To Suzuris, thank you so much for always watching over me and cheering me on!]
その姿が見えたから、ここまで来れてる かも分からなかった、じまんのおしになれるよう
[Letter: Seeing you support me helped me get this far. To become an oshi you can be proud of,]
これからもコツコツがんばっていくので ずっと見ててね
[Letter: I'll keep doing my best step by step, so please keep watching over me!]
すずががんばれるのは すずりすのおかげ！！
[Letter: The reason Suzu can keep going is all thanks to Suzuris!!]